# VED PRAKASH GUPTA

Software Engineer (Game Developer)

LINKEDIN WEBSITE

## **Summary**

Experienced Game Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the gaming industry. Skilled in Unity3D, Photon Networking, Socket Programming, VR, AR and Multiplayer. Strong engineering professional with a B.Tech focused in Computer Science and Engineering from Harcourt Butler Technological Institute, Kanpur.

### **Contact Information**

Address :Ram Brahma Nagar Colony, Secunderabad, Hyderabad, Telangana,IN

E-Mail :vedprakashgupta@outlook.com

Contact :+91 (809) 029 4477

## **Work Experience**

## Kravis Technologies Private Limited, Hyderabad, IN October 2017 - Present

Here, I am working as Game Developer on Unity3D, C#, Unreal Engine, AR, VR, Socket Programming etc technologies.

## Must Play Games Private Limited, Hyderabad, IN November 2015 - September 2017

Worked as a Software Engineer (Game Developer) and developed a wide variety of the games.

## Incord, Kanpur, IN Developer – 9 months

Designed and Developed the INCORD-2014 Official website. INCORD is the annual technical fest of the department of Computer Science and Engineering, HBTI (Harcourt Butler Technological Institute) Kanpur. It is organized by FCIT (Fraternity of Computer Science & Information Technologists) on behalf of all computer enthusiasts.

## **Projects**

#### **KAABIL: The Official Game**

A game that is based on Bollywood's blockbuster movie KAABIL. You have to navigate your character Hritik to his world.

#### Links:

**Android:** <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mustplay.kaabil&hl=en">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mustplay.kaabil&hl=en</a> <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/kaabil-the-official-game/id1192967057?mt=8">https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/kaabil-the-official-game/id1192967057?mt=8</a>

#### **Intruders: Robot Defense**

A game that is based on Tower Defense strategy. The whole game is with phenomenal outstanding gameplay experience. You have to defend your base from the enemies.

#### Links:

**Android**: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mustplay.intruders&hl=en">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mustplay.intruders&hl=en</a>
<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/intruders-robot-defense/id1171066744?mt=8">https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/intruders-robot-defense/id1171066744?mt=8</a>

#### The Cube Run

A game that is based on swipe control and have a set of lego characters. Simple and entertaining game with beautiful UI.

#### Link:

**Android:** <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.gamesara.thecube&hl=en">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.gamesara.thecube&hl=en</a>

## **Archviz Villa: An Architecture Visualization Application**

It is an application that intended to provide the architecture (Real Estate Projects e.g. Villa etc.) visualization in AR, VR and Walkthrough medium.

**Targeted Devices**: Android, iOS, Windows **Tools/GE**: Unity3D, Unreal Engine

**AR** : Vuforia

**VR** :Oculus, HTC Vive

#### **Furniture Pro:**

Furniture Pro is a Standalone application, which is designed to visualize the furniture products look and feel, and how it will affect the ambience of the house. It is having the options: creating the different shapes of house/villa, dragging the furniture product, customising colours and texture. Along with moveable windows and doors.

**Targeted Devices:** Windows **Tools/GE**: Unity3D

#### Bank AR:

Bank AR is the iOS and Android AR demo application that will show the augmented data related to scanned Credit/Debit card. Along with the transaction history, expenses, current offers etc.

Targeted Devices: Android, iOS

**Tools/GE** : Unity3D **AR** : EasyAR

#### **Furniture AR:**

It is a marker less AR iOS/Android application. That is developed to visualize the furniture product in real life in augmented way.

Targeted Devices: Android, iOS
Tools/GE : Unity3D AR
AR : AR Kit, Kudan

### **Skills**

Familiar Environment: Windows, Linux

Frameworks: ASP. NET

Database: AWS, SQLite

Languages: C#, C, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Game Engine: Unity 3D, Unreal Engine

Command Line Tools: Visual Studio Console

**Programming Architecture:** MVC, OOPs

**IDE:** Visual Studio, Mono Develop

Android AR SDKs: Vuforia, Kudan, EasyAR, Wikitude

iOS AR SDKs: AR Kit

**VR SDKs:** HTC Vive, Oculus, Google

### **Achievements**

**Microsoft Certified Professional:** Awarded by **Microsoft** as a "Microsoft Certified Professional".

**Microsoft Technical Associate:** Awarded by **Microsoft** as a "Microsoft Technical Associate".

**New Horizon:** Won 1st prize in Documentary/Seminar in NEW HORIZON, Seminar held by Maharana Pratap Polytechnic, Gorakhpur.

## **Training**

#### **ASP.NET with C#**

Summer Training on "ASP.NET with C#" **H.P. (Hewlett-Packard) Education Service**, Greater Noida.

### **Education**

## **Bachelor in Technology - Computer Science**

Harcourt Butler Technological Institute (U.P.T.U.) Graduated 2015 Kanpur, IN

## Diploma - Mechanical (Computer Aided Design)

Maharana Pratap Polytechnic, Gorakhpur, IN

## **Personal Info**

**Date of Birth** : 04-July-1994

**Language Known** : English, Hindi

Marital Status : Unmarried

**Nationality**: Indian

## **Position And Responsibilities**

**CLASS REPRESENTATIVE** of 2014-15 batch CSE Dept., HBTI-Kanpur.

"DESIGNING AND MEDIA HEAD" was at INCORD-2014, the annual technical festival of Computer Science and Engineering Dept., HBTI Kanpur.

## Developed & Designed the INCORD-2014 Website-

http://incordhbti.org/incord2014/

**Head Co-ordinator** in **VISION BOTICS** workshop at INCORD-2014, CSE Dept., HBTIKanpur.

**Head Co-ordinator** in **ETHICAL HACKING** workshop at INCORD-2014, CSE Dept., HBTI-Kanpur.

**Head Co-ordinator** in **B-Plan(BUSSINESS PLAN)** event at INCORD-2014,CSE Dept., HBTI-Kanpur.

**Active Member** of **FCIT**(Fratinity of Computer Science & Information Technologist), CSE

## References

**Dr. Raghuraj Singh**, Former Head CSE Dept. HBTI Kanpur, Presently Director, KNIT, Sultanpur +91-9721456082, www.raghuraj.info

**Dr. Prabhat Verma**, Asst. Professor, CSE Dept., HBTI Kanpur, +919721456019, pvluk@yahoo.com